

# Neil Mallia

The Residence, Triq San Gwann Gharghur, Malta **E-mail:** neil.mallia1@gmail.com **Phone:** 77201093

### **OBJECTIVE**

An ex-chef that recently changed profession due to a newly found passion for web and software development.

Zend Certified Engineer, I specialise in PHP and Laravel framework. Familiar with modern design patterns, MVC architecture, and building RESTful APIs. Looking forward to further develop skills in Laravel Framework and enhance my technical skills in the development of web and software applications.

I'm passionate about learning new technologies and consider my self to be a fast learner and look forward to working in a team, together with other developers.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### freelance

january 2023 - present

Freelance web-developer

### Wigis Kitchen

January 2019 - april2023

Chef

- Oversee kitchen operations and ensure the timely preparation and delivery of high-quality dishes.
- Collaborate with management to develop menus on daily basis that align the restaurants vision and customer preference.
- Train and mentor kitchen staff to ensure consistent execution of recipes and adherence to food safety guidelines

### Ubistrot

February 2010 — December 2018

Chef

- Led a team of 10 kitchen staff, managing all aspects of food preparation and service for a high-end Bistrot
- Designed and implemented innovative menus that reflected changing seasonal offerings and dietary trends
- Coordinating with front of house staff to ensure a seamless and enjoyable dining experience for customers

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

#### Zend Certified Engineer (ZCE)

Engineer ID: ZEND033558

https://www.zend-zce.com/en/services/certification/zend-certified-engineer-directory#cid=135&certtype=&firstname=&lastname=&company=&ClientCandidateID=ZEND033

#### Adobe Certified Professional (ACP)

Adobe Certification: https://www.credly.com/badges/9d9ac360-44f4-43f3-9242-6c1983cd78be/

### Degree In Culinary arts

Neil Mallia

### **PHP Zend Engineer**

August 2022 — February 2023

Institute of Computer Education Malta

PHP fundamentals and advanced.

MYSOL.

**RESTful APIs** 

Architectural design Patterns

### Adobe certified professional

August 2022 — December 2022

Institute of Computer Education Malta

Adobe certified web-author with adobe Dreamweaver.

### **Degree in Culinary Arts**

September 2007 — September

2011

Institute of tourism studies

Diploma In Culinary Arts

#### **INTERESTS**

- Web-development
- Music
- Scuba-diving
- Adventure and Traveling

#### **LANGUAGES**

### Spoken and written Languages:

- Maltese
- English
- Italian

## Computer Languages:

### Front-end:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript ES6
- Jquery
- AJAX
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS

### Back-end:

- PHP
- SQL
- Laravel Framework

### **Additional Skills:**

- Version Control (git)
- Package Manager (NPM, composer)
- API Development (RESTful)
- Database Management System (MySQL)
- Content Management System (Wordpress)

Neil Mallia

2

Neil Mallia 3